A Guide to the Thomas Lee Scott Papers, 1834-1865
Scott, Thomas Lee, papers
1834-1865
Scott, Thomas Lee, 1820-
1920
(18 items.)
Dolph Briscoe Center for American History, The University of Texas at Austin
Financial documents, civic records, and personal correspondence compose the Thomas Lee Scott Papers, 1834-1865.
Biographical Note
Thomas Lee Scott was born in 1820 in Independence, Texas. A farmer by trade, he lived in Washington County, Texas with his wife Mary E. Scott. In the 1850s the family owned slaves. During the American Civil War Scott served as a soldier in the Confederate Army. He was granted amnesty after the war ended in 1865.
Scope and Contents
Financial documents, civic records, and personal correspondence compose the Thomas Lee Scott Papers, 1834-1865. Materials relating to the American Civil War include Confederate war tax receipts, military orders, and Thomas Lee Scott’s signed Amnesty Oath. Scott’s civilian life is represented by a dinner invitation from Miss A. R. Holmes and bills of sale for the purchase of slaves from John L. Young and Mary E. Coles. The collection also features an undated poem signed by J. C. Hill and an 1834 marriage bond between John Thompson and Jane A. Gossett.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research use.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Scott, Thomas Lee, 1820- -- Archives; Scott, Mary E.; Thompson, John; Gossett, Jane A.
Subjects (Organizations)
Confederate States of America -- Armed Forces
Subjects
American Civil War -- Texas; Slavery -- 1850-1860; War Tax -- Receipts
Places
Washington County (Tex.) -- History -- 19th century
Detailed Description of the Papers
- Inventory
  - Amnesty Oath, 1865 (1 item) (Box 2G180)
  - Bills of Sale, 1852-1853 (2 items)
  - Confederate War Tax Receipts, 1861-1865 (7 items)
  - Marriage Bond, 1834 (1 item)
  - Military Orders, 1863, undated (2 items)
  - Invitation, 1852 (1 item)
  - Envelopes, 1852, undated (2 items)
  - Pay stub, 1864 (1 item)
  - Poem, undated (1 item)